<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mentorship on Tremor</title><link>/tags/mentorship/</link><description>Recent content in mentorship on Tremor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 17:25:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/mentorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Property Based Testing of Tremor Script</title><link>/blog/2021-07-06-blog-rohit-property-based-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 17:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-07-06-blog-rohit-property-based-testing/</guid><description>Introduction Hey, I am Rohit Dandamudi from India, about to complete my undergrad in CSE and will be working as a Software Engineer soon. I will be sharing my expereince at Tremor :)
Main motivation for applying My work involved writing &amp;ldquo;Property-based tests for tremor-script&amp;rdquo; and some of the reasons for applying are:
It involved a new type of testing I never heard of Be part of a sandbox project where I can learn and grow with the community The concept of learning Erlang + Rust was very interesting to me and frankly out of my comfort zone, as a person used to Python and web development in general.</description></item><item><title>Support for the Syslog Protocol</title><link>/blog/2021-07-05-lfx-blog-nupur/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 11:04:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-07-05-lfx-blog-nupur/</guid><description>Introduction Hey folks, I am Nupur Agrawal, a third year student at Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee. This blog describes my experience of contributing to Tremor, CNCF sandbox project in the 2021 spring chapter of LFX Mentorship Program, under the mentorship of Matthias Wahl, Anup Dhamala and Heinz Gies.
Project Abstract Tremor is an event processing system originally designed for the needs of platform engineering and infrastructure. It is built for the users that have a high message volume to deal with and want to build pipelines to process, route, or limit this event stream.</description></item><item><title>Google Cloud Storage and Pub/Sub connectors</title><link>/blog/2021-06-29t17-lfx-blog-jigyasa-gcloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 17:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-06-29t17-lfx-blog-jigyasa-gcloud/</guid><description>Introduction Hello folks! I&amp;rsquo;m Jigyasa, a final-year computer science engineering student at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women pursuing my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in Technology. This blog is about my experience contributing to Tremor as part of the LFX Mentorship program.
Learning about Tremor Tremor is an event processing system for unstructured data with rich support for structural pattern matching, filtering, and transformation. It is built for users that have a high message volume to deal with and want to build pipelines to process, route, or limit this event stream.</description></item></channel></rss>