<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>general on Tremor</title><link>/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on Tremor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 17:25:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jigyasa's LFX spring Mentorship experience report</title><link>/blog/2021-06-29t17-lfx-blog-jigyasa-gcloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 17:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-06-29t17-lfx-blog-jigyasa-gcloud/</guid><description>Introduction Hello folks! I&amp;rsquo;m Jigyasa, a final-year computer science engineering student at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women pursuing my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in Technology. This blog is about my experience contributing to Tremor as part of the LFX Mentorship program.
Learning about Tremor Tremor is an event processing system for unstructured data with rich support for structural pattern matching, filtering, and transformation. It is built for users that have a high message volume to deal with and want to build pipelines to process, route, or limit this event stream.</description></item><item><title>Releasing Tremor v0.10!</title><link>/blog/2021-02-12-v010-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 17:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021-02-12-v010-release/</guid><description>Montage based upon photo by Ádám Berkecz on Unsplash
Summary This release is the last minor release before we start turning tremor into a truly distributed event processing and data distribution engine. We focused on small things that improve usability and ironed out some rough edges here and there.
TL;DR We extended our type system and codecs by the binary type. Elasticsearch offramp now supports Linked Transport. String interpolation done right, now with #{} instead of just {} Release now includes prebuilt binaries, DEB packages and RPMs New Release Artefacts To make your life easier installing and Tremor we added new release artefacts.</description></item><item><title>Releasing Tremor v0.9!</title><link>/blog/2020-10-16-v09-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-10-16-v09-release/</guid><description>Summary Tremor is an open source event processing and data distribution engine designed to interpose or intercept data in complex systems primarily to inject quality of service, correct data flows and to enrich or support complex traffic shaping, routing and load-balancing based on contextual, situational or content derived dynamic conditions.
Tremor has a powerful ETL language designed for flexibly pattern matching structured data such as JSON efficiently (SIMD-accelerated), and an easy to configure declarative flow-based SQL language designed for rich JSON-like data to describe data processing and data flow graphs with declarative QoS constraints.</description></item><item><title>To async or not to async</title><link>/blog/2020-08-06-to-async-or-not-to-async/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 04:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-08-06-to-async-or-not-to-async/</guid><description>With the upcoming tremor release, 0.9.0, we&amp;rsquo;re moving from threads as a basis for ramps and pipelines to async tasks.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about why this is significant, what is changing, and how the architecture is changing.
Note that this is not a comprehensive treatise on threads or async tasks.
The Tremor That Was (threads) Threads are a basic building block of programs that execute multiple pieces of code concurrently. The operating system is responsible for coordinating across competing resource demands.</description></item><item><title>Rust &amp; Tell Berlin March 2020</title><link>/blog/2020-03-31-rust-and-tell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-03-31-rust-and-tell/</guid><description>We had the great pleasure of spending some time with the crowd of Rust &amp;amp; Tell today. At the meetup, we got the chance to share some of the stories of tremor and Event Processing Cartography. Long story short, if you&amp;rsquo;re curious, the talk was recorded (we&amp;rsquo;ll add the link later), and we got the slides right here!</description></item><item><title>Improving our influx parser - a story in four acts</title><link>/blog/influx-perf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 10:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/influx-perf/</guid><description>Influx parsing performance Yesterday we spent the day on a report that our influx parser was slow, it turns out it indeed was.
This is an exciting topic as just a few days ago we gave a talk at BoBKonf 2020 on this topic so this is a great opportunity to show some of the topics and our process in action.
All the topics in this blog are links, the main one above this text is to the pull request, the titles of each section links to the commit that implements the topic discussed.</description></item><item><title>Tremor is now Open Source</title><link>/blog/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 20:02:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/welcome/</guid><description>The tremor project was released as an Open Source software project on 22nd February 2020 at 20:02:02.
Catch us at BOB2020 on the 28th February 2020 in Berlin where we will be talking about our usage of the Rust programming language to build high performance and high density production systems with Tremor.</description></item></channel></rss>